# 醋溜白菜
Quick Fried Napa Cabbage with Vinegar
# 这菜好
This is an awesome dish
# 易学易懂
Easy to understand and quick to learn
# 冬储大白菜
Napa cabbage is usually stored in large quantity during winter season
# 它在外边的筋太多
The outer layers have more hard stems
# 所以使中间这个
So we use the core parts mainly
# 芯里边还是好一点的
The inner layer of the napa cabbage is a better choice for this dish
# 要在选材的方面
The first key point,
# 好在哪儿
during the method of ingredient selection
# 其实这醋溜白菜
for this dish
# 第一个要点他说出来了
was told by him just now
# 第二个就是刀工了
The second point Is the cutting skill
# 刀工 抹刀
Slant-cut the napa cabbage
# 放点盐先杀一杀它的的水气
Put in some salt to remove excess moisture
# 他这第二个要点出来了
This is his second point
# 一般的白菜人家不杀
Amateur chefs don’t do this step usually
# 醋溜白菜的蒜是必须得放的
Garlic must be used in this dish
# 葱不起主要的味道
Onion is not the main flavour
# 然后有个干辣椒
And also dried chillies
# 它这里边没姜
There is not any ginger in this dish
# 要有姜不好吃了 完了
If you put ginger in it, the dish would not be tasty anymore
# 这是第三点很重要
This is the third key point
# 23
# 00:00:48,360
# 兑个醋溜白菜的汁
# Now let’s make the sauce
# 米醋80克
Rice vinegar 80g
# 鲜味酱油60克
Umami soy sauce 60g
# 然后放点糖
Then add some sugar
# 综合一下酱油当中的豆苦味
to balance with the slight bitterness of the soy sauce
# 盐3克
3g of salt
# 淀粉 这是玉米淀粉
Some corn starch
# 我们把这个锅里边放上底油
Add some base oil into the wok
# 油温六成热
Heat the oil until 180 °C
# 辣椒煸炒一下
Fry the chillies first
# 棕色
until they turned reddish brown
# 大火 一直是大火煸炒
Fry it with high flame
# 煸到这白菜基本要透明了
Fry the napa cabbage slices until they are mostly translucent
# 它就透了
then it is cooked
# 然后在汁里还要放点香油
We have to add some sesame oil into the sauce too
# 汁倒进锅之后只要淀粉糊化了
Fry the cabbage until the sauce thickens up
# 包在原料上面就可以了
and coats the cabbage slices
# 翻两下出锅了
Toss it for a few times and the dish is done
# 香味出来了
The dish is very aromatic now
# 最后要比别的菜的汁芡儿要大一点
The sauce should be thicker than the other dishes, with more slurry
# 表面光泽红亮
The dish should have a shiny surface with a slight hint of red
# 醋溜白菜
Quick Fried Napa Cabbage with Vinegar
# 这我还特别爱吃
This is one of my favourite dishes
# 第一口
First bite
# 里边有蒜香
There is the aroma of garlic in it
# 醋香
And the fragrance of the vinegar
# 辣香
Some slight spiciness
# 白菜的脆嫩
The crunchy texture of the cabbage
# 选料的时候
When you are choosing the ingredients,
# 一定是靠中间
you have to use the inner parts of the napa cabbage
# 往里的白菜帮好一些
Those layers are better
# 在刀工处理上
When you are cutting the cabbage,
# 两毫米半到三毫米厚
2mm to 3mm thick
# 这个厚度才合适
is a perfect thickness
# 汁的量
You should have a solid grasp of
# 要把握好
the amount of the sauce
# 少了就体现不出来
If the sauce is too little, then the dish would taste different
# 挂了这么多汁 不叫溜
If the sauce is too much, then this is not fried cabbage
# 太多了就会出的满盘子是汤
The dish would be cabbage soup
# 干辣椒一定要炸到这种棕红色
Dried chillies have to be fried until become brownish
# 才能出那种香味
then the aroma of it would be released
# 等这个碗芡下锅之后
When you pour the sauce with the slurry into the wok
# 不要忙着去使劲去搅它
Don’t stir it immediately
# 糊化了使勺推两下
When the sauce thickens up, use the wok ladle to stir it a few times
# 翻一下就可以出锅了
Toss it then it can be served